Previously on Dating Alys Perez.
You still love me, don't you, Alys?
I don't love you anymore!
Hi, Silly!
Tripp!
I saw Tripp yesterday.
My god, Alys.
He's gotten even more handsome.
Okay, kiss!
I missed you too!
Okay, kiss Auntie Alys, too!
No!
We have a problem.
Our wedding planner
cancelled.
Can you please step up for us?
Cristine's gone.
It's you and me again, Alys.
Make your groom happy.
You ready?
Good morning, Ms. Alys!
Good morning, Charmaine.
Is Mommy still abroad?
Yes, Ma'am.
God please help me.
Yes, Ma'am? Sorry?
Oh, nothing.
Never mind.
No, thanks.
Is this really necessary, Drake?
Good morning to you, too, Alys.
Come on.
Cristine and I aren't the same size.
Are you calling yourself fat?
Excuse me?!
What did you say?
Take that back.
How dare he call me fat?
Where's Ms. Stinson's gown?
Here, Ms. Perez.
This one.
We'll see who's fat.
If this really fits me,
you're in trouble!
One...
Two...
Three!
Ms. Alys, the gown might get damaged!
Shut up!
On the count of three,
you're gonna zip it up.
No matter what happens,
even if it gets torn, I don't care!
Yes, Ma'am. Understood.
Okay?!
- Okay, Ma'am!
- One more try.
One...
Two...
Three!
Are we good?
Yes, Ma'am. It fits!
It fits!
I really am Dana Ferrer
and Cyriel Perez's daughter.
He called me fat?
Who's fat now?
I'll show you, Drake Palma.
I'm very sorry, Sir.
But you may not see the bride.
Don't you believe the superstition?
The girl in that gown is Alys Perez.
If we were getting married,
do you think I'll let anyone stop me?
What marriage?
This guy's got some nerve.
But, Sir...
Excuse me, can you
leave us for a moment?
Yes, Ma'am.
Thank you.
Same...
old...
Alys.
Huh?
That's it?
I could barely breathe
just to fit into Cristine's gown.
And that's all he said?
Same old Alys?
So?
Where's the next destination?
Drake, what are we doing here?
What are we doing, Alys?
Why the hell is
everything so confusing?
Ever since I met Drake,
“Complicated” became my middle name.
Fuck off, Drake!
Yes, Drake.
This is who I am.
I'm not the same old
Alys that you left years ago.
You left me, remember?
You left me to freakin’ grow up.
Now, I curse.
I drink —
Hell, I even gamble if I want to.
Look at me.
I grew up.
And I don't want to be
with you any longer.
So, please, please...
Leave me alone!
Please don't start where we left off,
because I don't want
to start over with you.
I want to continue
living my life as it is.
Peacefully.
I can take whatever
you give me, Alys.
But don't underestimate
how I feel about you.
Childish or not, you're still Alys...
I don't want to be with you!
What the hell is
fucking wrong with you?
Are you fucking obsessed with me?
You're getting married to Cristine!
Are you insane?!
I still have time to back out, Alys.
Please!
Drake!
Drink and forget.
Drink until you forget.
Can you feel that?
That's the heartbeat of a man
who's obsessed with you.
Throw me a bone, Alys.
I'll pick it up for you,
no matter what.
I'm yours, Alys.
So, deal with it.
All the complications are coming back.
And I really don't quite like it.
Tonight, I'm coming clean.
I don't want to fight with Tripp.
I can't lose him.
Hell, I don't want to lose him.
I gave your heart back
a long time ago, Drake.
Find anyone else but me!
You won't get anything
from me anymore.
I'm happy with you, Alys.
So, I'll stay.
You...
disgust me!
Manang, where is Tripp?
In his office, Ma'am.
Hey!
Are we getting married now, Perez?
Ha ha ha.
Very funny.
What's with the wedding gown?
Let me guess.
Runaway Bride?
I told you,
stop watching too many movies?
Tripp...
What's wrong?
Well, I'm wearing a wedding gown.
And you look decent enough.
The only thing missing is the ring.
Are you proposing to me, Perez?
I'll have to speak to Uncle Cyriel first.
Okay?
Slow down.
Wow.
Big words coming from you.
I will propose one day.
Just chill.
We'll get there someday.
Okay?
Why are you wearing a wedding dress?
No reason.
Just a little preview for you.
I look pretty, right?
Fine.
You are pretty.
Wow, that sounded so forced.
It’s not.
You're too beautiful.
More than too much.
Why do I feel so guilty?
This isn't right.
Marco!
You kept this?
Of course.
Cute!
You know,
if Dad sees us like this,
he might get the wrong idea.
Yeah, right.
As if, Marco.
So, why were you wearing
a wedding dress?
You want the truth?
Yes, the truth.
I don't want us to fight, but...
It's better that he hears it from me
than from someone else.
Marco, it's...
It's Drake.
And?
What is it?
I'm sorry, Marco.
Drake is Cristine's groom.
I promise I never intended
to keep it from you, but.
I didn't want us to fight.
Please don't be mad.
I'm sorry.
I trust you.
You do?
Really?
I trust you so much, Alys.
Even if I don't trust Drake.
So, you and Drake aren't
going to talk anymore?
Two years, Alys.
In those two years,
did I ever make a move?
I didn't, right?
In those two years,
I waited
before I courted you.
And now he says
that I took you away?
So, no.
We're not speaking.
Okay.
I understand.
Come on, don't frown.
Smile.
Come on, smile.
Like that, smile with teeth.
Come on, smile with teeth.
I love you, Marco.
I love you, Zy.
It’s happening.
This is exactly what I’m afraid of.
Drake is coming back.
Thank you, nanny.
Please prepare an affogato for later.
Okay po, Ma’am.
Thank you.
Marco...
Hmm?
It's hot!
The food you’re cooking, or...
you?
Marco...
- What?
- Marco!
I just missed you.
It's only been a few minutes
since we last saw each other.
That's the thing.
You're so stubborn!
Go over there for now!
I’ll stay here, please.
I can't concentrate on cooking like this
if you’ll stay here.
Do you want to eat burnt steak?
Come on, go ahead.
I'll call you when I'm done, okay?
There, good boy.
Yes, your Majesty.
Hey, Silly.
This is the invitation to
their annual family reunion.
Oh my gosh!
My god!
What do you have there?
Why are you still hiding it?
I already saw it.
Didn't I tell you that I'd call
you when food is ready?
When the food is ready?
- Marco!
- Is the food ready?
Behave yourself!
Are you sure?
Tripp!
- Stop that!
- Why?
I'm not doing anything.
What is it?
Oh!
The food is ready?
Hey!
Will you go with me?
Huh?
I said...
Will you be my date
for the reunion?
I thought you didn't want me to go.
Well,
you've already seen Drake so...
I don't think there's
a reason not to go.
I thought you didn't
want to talk to Drake.
I don't.
But, it's not like I can avoid it.
He's my cousin.
That's true.
So?
What do you mean, so?
Is that a yes?
Bless you.
Take some medicine.
Before it gets worse.
No, I'll be fine.
It's probably all the
pepper on the steak.
Hey!
- All the pepper?
- I'm sorry. Excuse me.
You're blaming the pepper now?
Okay, let's go.
Let’s just eat.
Come on, Silly.
Let's get some food.
But I don't want to.
Just eat, will you?
Sick.
Can't come reunion.
Sleep.
No, it's cold.
Drake?
You're not well, Alys Perez.
Of all the things I hate,
is you looking weak.
Don't you know that?
Of course, you don’t.
Who am I to you, anyway?
Oh, right.
This will be the only chance
I have for you to listen.
Because every time I say something,
you always pick a fight with me.
Why are you being
so stubborn, Alys?
Are you mad at me because
of what happened in New York?
I really want to say yes.
I really want to know why he left.
But there's also this part of me
that doesn't want to know.
Don't listen, Alys.
You're happy now.
Do not listen to a word he says.
He will just ruin everything.
Like what he did to you before.
Do you really want to know?
Ask me, Alys.
I just hope you won't get mad
that I didn't tell you why I left you.
Alys!
What's wrong with you?
I'm so stupid.
Oh, well.
What's done is done.
Here.
Eat.
Porridge?
Don't be picky.
Do I look like I know
how to cook?
Who asked you to do the cooking?
We have the nannies for that.
"Thanks, Dane!"
"Best brother ever."
Thank you, Baby Dane!
Stop!
Quit it.
This little brat.
He acts like he's four years
older than me.
This is pretty sweet though.
Tastes fine.
Ask me, Alys.
I just hope you won't get mad
that I didn't tell you why I left you.
Seriously,
do I really have to ask him?
What's wrong with me?
I'm happy with my life.
Do I really have to
complicate things again?
Bestie!
Who are you talking to?
No one.
I'm just talking to myself.
Aunt Dana said you’re sick.
I see.
So, you're staying in?
Great!
Let's do a movie marathon!
I have a better idea!
Tell me everything.
About what?
About Drake!
Come on, come on!
What's with you, Aya?
What do you think
my life is with Drake?
A soap opera?
Do I have to update you
on every little thing?
Come on, Bestie.
I was just a little curious.
If they push through with
their wedding next week,
does that mean...
it's really game over for DrAlys?
Ouch!
Aya Pineda, you're such a gossip!
You better fix yourself.
You're getting too old for that.
But seriously, Bestie.
It's endgame if they're getting married.
Hey!
What the are you talking about?!
Get a grip, Aya!
But seriously, Bestie,
DrAlys 'til the end of time!
Really?
I don't believe you.
Didn't you say recently,
"Wow, Tripp's so handsome!"
And now it's "DrAlys forever!"
Seriously, Alys.
What happens now?
What do you mean,
what happens now?
We broke up.
Remember?
Yeah, there has to be a reason.
But...
What's Drake's reason?
Do you know?
I don't know.
And I don't want to know.
Alys!
You should ask him!
I don't want to!
Listen to me, Alys.
Once and for all,
ask him!
Alys Zyril Ferrer Perez!
Ask him!
And if you still don't
want to be with him,
I'll shut up for life!
Aya!
Tripp is a good man.
Can't I just choose him instead?
Can't I just be with him instead?
Yeah.
You and Tripp,
good together.
But Bestie,
Bestie!
You and Drake,
Epic together!
Bestie, you might have
gotten me sick, too.
- Sorry, bestie.
- And that's the truth!
Sorry, bestie.
Yeah.
We were epic when
we were together.
We had our time.
So, now,
are you going to talk to him?
Fine, yes.
Whatever.
Good answer, Bestie!
Okay, hold on, I'll call him.
Stay there, wait.
- Huh?!
- He’s downstairs.
I’ll just call him.
What do you mean “I'll call him”?
Hey!
Aya!
It's okay, Alys.
Everything will be alright.
Drake?
Talk.
It’s because you made me
your whole world
back then, Alys.
That's it?
No complicated shit?
No mind-bending reason?
Not even an implausible excuse?
That’s it?
Just plain...
"I can't keep a love life and keep
living my life at the same time?"
That's crap.
That's it?
It’s not only that, Alys.
I left you because you were
ruining your life over me.
You don't get to decide
what's good for me, Drake!
Back then, I could.
I was your boyfriend, Alys.
And I knew,
that we'd ruin each other
if we stayed that way.
It wasn't worth it when you
had so much ahead of you.
I wasn't pulling shits!
What is this about?
My studies?
News flash.
I was never smart,
Mr. Genius.
You think leaving me would
magically make me smart?
It didn't.
I dropped out.
Did you know that, Drake?
Did you know what
you put me through?
You were my boyfriend!
Weren't you?!
You were supposed to be the one
helping and encouraging me to study!
I was in New York.
I was alone.
I barely knew anyone.
Shit, I’ve never
felt so alone.
Only then, Drake.
Wherever I'd look,
I couldn't recognize anyone.
I couldn't talk to anyone.
Drake, I was so
fucking lonely.
Do you remember?
The day I left on that rooftop?
Do you know
how badly I wanted you
to stop me?
"Alys, don't go."
That's all I wanted to hear.
That's all.
Three words.
Ten letters.
But you didn't even give me that.
Did you even know that, Drake?
I loved you so fucking much!
To the point that I begged
my parents to let me stay!
Did you know that?
What do you know about me?
All you ever knew
was Alys Zyril Perez,
who tried so hard
to be your girlfriend.
Now that I've mentioned it,
I feel so cheap.
That's what you must think of me.
A little dog!
I was like a dog!
Following you around.
Shit, I wait for your
fucking command.
Is that why it was easy
to take me for granted?
Because you know what,
whatever you did,
even if you did nothing,
I would be there.
I loved you over and over again, Drake!
And you fucked me over.
I was so easy to
leave behind, wasn't I?
That was the reason you left me?
What the fucking hell!
You’re so funny!
I love you.
There.
There it is.
Every time he's like this,
I lose myself.
But I don't want this anymore.
Please.
Enough.
Are you finished, Alys?
No, Drake.
I'll never be finished with you.
And you'll never hear the end of it.
Good.
Because I couldn't care less
about whatever you say, Alys.
As long as you speak to me,
I'll be happy.
Don't cry.
Talk.
I'd rather not, Alys.
Because every time I talk,
you always cry.
When you talk,
I listen.
When I talk,
you cry.
So, I'd rather not.
Fine.
That's how it is, Drake.
Are you mad, too?
Because I am really fucking mad.
Drake, talk.
Stop crying.
Please, Alys.
You don't get to decide
for me now, Drake.
You're not my boyfriend anymore.
I know.
But I love you so much, Alys.
I loved you then,
until now.
You just haven't accepted it.
Or you just don't want to.
Please, Drake.
Please...
Stop saying that you love me.
I love Tripp.
I'm still in love with you, Alys.
Always.
You always call me selfish.
But, Alys, how was that selfish?
I put your well being first,
before my own feelings.
I did everything I could
to stay in your life.
Even when we were apart,
I tried to follow you.
But the more I watch you,
there’s one thing
I can’t accept.
You're slowly ruining
your life because of me.
I couldn't bear to watch.
Because I love you.
I love you so much.
Alys.
I can love you without
forgetting about myself.
You can't.
I can.
No, Alys.
And every time you
try to choose me,
there’s one thing you always forget.
I can't bear to watch that, Alys.
Fuck you, Drake!
All I did was fucking love you!
I just loved you!
What was so wrong with that?
All I did was love you!
In your eyes,
all you did was love me.
The way I see it,
you're forgetting who you are.
Are you saying,
that I was destroying my life
when I was dating you?
No, Drake.
Get this through your thick head!
You...
You broke me when you
left me in New York!
I didn't break myself.
You did!
No, Alys.
I stopped you
from destroying yourself.
Listen to me, Alys.
I never ever asked
that you love me at
the cost of your life.
I'd never ask you
to choose me.
If someone has to do the chasing,
let it be me.
If someone has to wait,
If someone has to get hurt,
let it be me, Alys.
No, Drake.
That's enough.
Alys, I will wait for you
if you tell me to.
I'm willing to love you, Alys,
while you're living your best life.
I'm willing to be the fool, Alys.
Just say yes.
Please say yes, Alys.
I'm begging you.
I'll be waiting, Alys.
I'll be waiting.
I can handle the pain.
And I can give you all my love.
I'll wait for you, Alys.
Just give me a chance.
It's been three days
since I talked to Drake.
And I haven't slept.
I've been avoiding Tripp, too.
Shit, I feel so guilty.
It feels like I'm playing with them.
I know I shouldn't.
Hey!
What happened to you?
Nothing.
I'm a little stressed about
Drake and Cristine's wedding.
What?
What is it now?
Tell me the truth, Alys.
Do you need a handout?
And what makes you think that?
Well,
it's just a thought. Because...
Think about it.
Why would you choose
to be the wedding planner
for your own ex?
Right?
Of course.
It's the only explanation
I thought of. It’s either...
You're broke,
or a real masochist.
I have my reasons, okay?
It's none of your business.
Whatever you say.
But Alys,
get it together.
You know,
one of these days,
one of those two brain
cells is going to give out.
That's harsh.
Oh, Alys!
Since you're the wedding planner...
Yeah?
Could I
get an invitation?
Why?
You weren't invited?
You know that me and Drake
are basically Tom and Jerry.
Right?
Of course, I wasn't.
Come on!
Squeeze me into the guest list.
Okay, but...
But?
Tell me why Drake
is so mad at you.
In your dreams, Perez.
Okay!
Then no invites for you.
You'll just have to crash it.
Whatever.
But I do have a question.
Hmm?
Is Drake’s wedding real or...
just a scam?
Why would it be a scam?
To tell you honestly,
no one in the family knows
that a wedding is about to happen.
What?!
What? Explain it clearly!
Just relax, okay?
Spit it out!
The thing is...
I asked Mom, Dad
and even grandma.
Nobody's heard of a wedding!
They even thought it was a prank!
And did you know...
Know what?!
Spit it out!
Enough with the suspense already!
So, here's the thing.
When I asked grandma,
all she said was...
“Drake?”
“I don't know anything
about a wedding, dear.”
“All I know is what Steve told me.”
“Drake's just waiting for
his girlfriend who's abroad.”
Don't you get it?
Jeez, thank god Tripp wasn't there!
If he was there? Well...
It'd be World War II in the Palma family.
No, Alys.
You're not the only girl who went abroad.
Don't assume.
But, damn,
stop lying to yourself, Alys.
You're clearly the one Drake
was talking about.
Drake and his crooked world.
You know,
I always thought it was Shaira
those two were fighting over.
Turns out it was just you.
How about sending some
of that beauty, Perez?
I’ll really kill him!
Hey, just relax!
That's expensive!
Charmaine, don't forget
about the 2:00 PM delivery.
Bestie!
- Bestie!
You know, this is the first time
I've seen you at Mom's boutique.
I thought you’re
a ghost employee.
Whatever.
What are you doing here, anyway?
Well, I'm here to pick up
Ms. Stinson's gown.
I'm taking it to Batangas.
Wedding's in a few days.
My god.
You'll forever be the martyr.
I don't know what to do with you.
Gosh.
Weren't you the one
pushing me and Drake to talk?
And now you're going
on about me being a martyr?
Ms. Alys!
Both the gown and the
mannequin are in your car, Ma'am.
Okay, thank you!
Bestie,
let's get an early lunch, first.
Oh, no. I can't, Bestie.
I'm leaving right now,
because an early lunch
with you will last all evening.
I know you too well.
If I let you gossip,
I'll never be able to leave.
What about early dinner instead?
- Don't you want to hear the tea?
- Oh, late dinner?
I do.
My gosh.
- Why?
- Gosh, so annoying.
Are you going out with Kent?
Are you getting back together with.
"Bee!"
- "Bee!"
- Bestie, that’s enough.
Just go already. That’s right, go!
"Bee!"
I'll be going now.
- Bye, Bestie! I love you.
- You’re crazy.
"Bee!"
My bestie!
Is she crazy?
I asked Mom, Dad
and even grandma.
Nobody's heard of a wedding!
They even thought it was a prank!
What is that Tofer talking about?
I've invested too much into
this for it to be a fake wedding.
What is this then?
What is it for?
Hi, Silly!
Anything interesting?
Hey!
Are we getting married now, Perez?
What's with the wedding gown?
I'll wait for you, Alys.
Just give me a chance.
You're the worst, Alys.
How could you do this to him?
Tripp.
Zy?
Tripp, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry, Tripp.
What?
What do you mean, sorry?
I love you, okay?
What?!
What are you talking about?
What-
I hate to tell it to your face, Tripp.
You don’t deserve this.
My god!
I missed the Philippines!
But I didn't miss you, Drake.
You're still so ugly.
Stupid.
What do you mean, stupid?
And here I was doing you a favor!
You know I hate flying to Canada.
But I did it for you.
Fine, thank you.
Now, you’re thanking me.
You're annoying.
Why did you go to Canada though?
You should have gone
to the other place, then.
Stupid.
Ugh! The nerve!
Ingrate!
Tattletale!
Bastard!
Flirt.
No, I'm not!
Oh!
I almost forgot.
I met someone over there.
Her name's Fier.
She's so pretty!
I invited her to take a vacation
here in the Philippines.
If you want, I'll introduce you
so you'll have another friend.
No.
Just shut up.
That would be so much better.
You're so grumpy.
Oh, wait.
Where's the gown?
Is this really the gown?!
Oh my god! It's so pretty!
You'll drop dead when
you see Alys in this!
She's always beautiful.
Idiot.
You can't pull that off.
But that's good.
Improving.
You're not stoic anymore.
Just a little.
Please, please...
What the hell is happening?
I want to call out and
ask them, but I can't.
I'm afraid of what I'll find out.
All these things...
Damn it!
It all makes sense now.
The gown, the place...
The fact that the Palmas don't
know he's getting married.
How everyone still
thinks I'm his girlfriend.
All the chasing and the screaming.
Drake...
I just wish your plan doesn't backfire.
I mean,
I've done my part,
you did your begging.
Now it's up to Alys.
If she'll say, yes.
And I do hope she'll say yes.
Wait. When's the proposal?
Damn this life.
It's only been a month since I got back.
But I've gone through so much already.
I wish I'd never come back.
The day before the wedding.
Okay, well...
What if she doesn't accept?
She will.
Whoa!
Somebody's got confidence.
Go, Drake.
Shut up.
I know Alys will say yes.
What —.
Think, Alys, think!
Thank you, Nanny.
Oh!
So it's true.
You've been chasing Alys.
What are you planning, Drake?
To hurt my best friend again?
I want us to get back together.
Now?
Why?
After everything,
you suddenly want her again?
You really are something.
What do you think this is?
Highschool all over again?
Nothing's changed, Aya.
I still love her.
No, Drake.
You don't hurt the person you love.
Did you know I almost
put a hex on you?
You hurt Alys!
She barely survived!
I was there!
I saw how hurt Alys was!
My best friend!
Maybe.
But I had no choice.
Are you insane, Drake Palma?
Are you a sadist?!
You say you love her
and then you hurt her?
Aya, you know what
Alys is going through.
She'd fail if I hadn't left her.
I chose to be the villain.
Rather than stop her from succeeding.
She failed NYCU!
She dropped out.
And now she's successful.
But in pain!
Is that what you wanted, Drake?
No.
And you know that.
Whatever!
Stay there.
I'll talk to her.
Aya, do you think...
That's her decision to make.
Only she can know
if she still wants to.
But one thing's for certain...
What you did to her
is something she'll never forget.
Something she'll never forgive.
I can only help so much.
And don't even think of abusing my help.
If you do,
I'll make sure to put a hex on you.
Stay there!
Thank you, Aya.
Drake.
I am watching you.
You reap what you sow.
Dane, how's Bestie?
I think she's better.
Bestie!
Who are you talking to, Bestie?
On the next episode of
Dating Alys Perez.
It hurts too much, Mommy.
Is this about Drake again?
Are you sure Alys is happy with you?
I'm sorry!
Would you like to know
how she looks at me
even when she's mad at me?
Marco?!
Motherfucker!
- You fucking asshole!
- Alys still loves me.
I can feel it, Tripp.
- Alys.
You two!
Just stop already!
Give me a little space to breathe!
Tripp?
What happened to you?